

Jessica **Ansong**

coderfoundry.com/jessicaansong

FRAMEWORKS & PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

C#
MVC
.NET
JavaScript
HTML5
CSS
ASP.NET
MVC
SQL
LINQ
RAZOR
Bootstrap
SQL Server

Entity Framework

CODER

1231 Shields Road, Suite 5 Kernersville, NC 27284

(336) 231-8632

partnerships@coderfoundry.com

This resume contains information furnished by the candidate and has not been independently verified by Coder Foundry, LLC.

This information is privileged, confidential, and to be used solely by the individual and entity to which it has been submitted.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Coder Foundry, Web Applications Developer

Kernersville, NC · June 2015-Present

- Created a personal portfolio website using C#, MVC5, and JavaScript. Design and developed front-end using HTML5, Twitter Bootstrap, and MVC model binding with Razor. Included secure log-in and blog web interface with user comments.
 Presented programming exercises and code snippets using JavaScript.
- Created a fully functional MVC bug tracker web application form scratch. Handled secure file upload functionality for approved file types. Implemented code first database with user- and role-level security. Database interaction done through LINQ to Entity framework
- Created a fully functioning WebAPI car finder web application form scratch.
 Composed dynamic, responsive front-end design using HTML5, and Twitter
 Bootstrap. Accessed NHTSA's car recalls database using provided WebAPI to show car recalls. Included images using Bing's WebAPI

Uber Technologies, Inc., Office Manager

Atlanta, GA · June 2014–July 2015

- Lead various programs that help boost morale and offer a productive environment for a 17-member team
- Deliver training to new driver partners on how to use the Uber mobile application; introduce creative strategies for partners, team members, and others to streamline processes and enhance the quality of their work
- Increased the number of active drivers on the Uber system; launch programs that help reduce company costs by 30%

Urban League of Greater Atlanta, Program Manager

Atlanta, GA · March 2013–March 2014

- Launched and managed the organization's first ever health and wellness program focused on improving the health of pregnant adolescents in low-income communities
- Collaborated with funders to develop and negotiate work plans and timelines;
 maintained effective communication with funders and program stakeholders;
 adhered to funder guidelines
- Improved participants' knowledge of healthy lifestyles by 88% and increased the organization's capacity to deliver health educational services to its clients

Global Green Miniature Clinics/Green EPD Builders, Marketing Strategist Atlanta, GA · January 2012—September 2014

- Collaborated with a team of business executives to devise a plan that helped deliver quality, cost-efficient medical care to the most remote regions of the world; conducted market research to help inform this start-up's business model
- Liaise with government officials in West African countries to coordinate efforts to install pre-fabricated miniature medical facilities in various countries
- Increase healthcare access for individuals living in the most remote areas of India; increase company revenue substantially

WORK EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Spectrum Health Policy Research Group, Evaluation Analyst II

Lawrenceville, GA · January 2012-June 2012

- Managed multiple evaluation projects for various health promotional programs; programs focused on violence, obesity, and heart disease prevention
- Conducted quantitative and qualitative analysis; maintained evaluation data in the company's unique data management system called Catalyst
- Influenced South Dakota and Kansas health departments' delivery of high quality health services within their respective states; and contributed to the successes of one of the fastest growing small businesses

The Balm in Gilead, Inc., Evaluation Specialist

Richmond, VA · May 2010-May 2011

- Led all evaluation activities for the organization's health behavioral programs; designed logic models and evaluation plans and developed data collection instruments
- Facilitated trainings on the methods and techniques on program evaluation for various community stakeholders
- Managed the evaluation activities for a \$200,000 government grant; monitored programs and ensured that all objectives were being met
- Provided input in developing new projects and collaborated with executive management to prepare successful grant proposals; drafted the introduction and monitoring and evaluation sections of grant proposals
- Produced two abstracts that were presented at the 2011 HIV Caribbean Conference (in Nassau, The Bahamas) and the National HIV Conference 2011 (in Atlanta, GA)

John Snow, Inc, Evaluation Assistant, Build Her Up Program

Boston, MA · May 2009- Dec 2009

- Supported and supervised the daily evaluation activities of small community-based public health programs; provided technical assistance in data management, data analysis; and data collection strategies
- Identified key indicators and implemented monitoring and evaluation plans that supported the program's overall goal
- Contributed to the Program's success in preventing risky behaviors among 40 at-risk young adults in Boston

Boston Public Health Commission, Research Assistant

Boston, MA · January 2008–April 2009

- Contributing writer and editor of the Health of Boston 2008 and the Health of Boston 2009, which highlighted health equities among Boston residents
- Implemented a process evaluation plan to assess the Boston Collaborative for Food and Fitness Youth Pilot Program (BCFF), a program designed to increase children's physical activity
- Recommended improvements for BCFF participants to increase their health outcomes

Ministry of Health - Jamaica, Field Research Team Lead

Jamaica, West Indies · May 2007-August 2007

- Led the research team in Jamaica in educating, counseling, and conducting research on HIV/AIDS patients in the western region
- Provided direction to research team members to fulfill research goals and objectives and collaborated with them to interview patients diagnosed with HIV/AIDS
- Recognized for outstanding research capabilities and extensive knowledge of behaviors associated with HIV/AIDS; appointed research team lead

EDUCATION

- Boston University School of Public Health, Boston, MA, May 2009, Master of Public Health – Social and Behavioral Sciences
- Spelman College, Atlanta, GA, May 2007, Bachelor of Arts Psychology

PAPERS AND PUBLICATIONS

- Ncube, N., Ansong J., Daniels, K. Campbell-Stennett, D., Reimer, R., Jolly, P. E. (2013). "Sexual risk behavior among HIV-positive persons in Jamaica." Manuscript submitted for publication.
- Shah, S.N., Dodds, H.D., Dooley, D., Sims, P.D. et al. (2009). "Health of Boston 2009." (Contributing writer)
- Shah, S.N., Dodds, H.D., Dooley, D., Sims, P.D. et al. (2008). "Health of Boston 2008." (Contributing writer)

SKILLS

Population Health, Monitoring & Evaluation, Technical Writing, Research, Statistical Analysis, Quantitative Analysis, Qualitative Analysis, Social Media, SAS, SPSS, English, Spanish, Twi